Hello welcome to module 14 of setting up
a journal with OJS 3.0 the static pages
plug-in. Static pages are additional HTML
content pages that are not part of the
basic OJS package, but will become part
of your website if, for example, you
wanted to add an information page about
an upcoming conference, this tool would
provide you with the capability to do so.
To activate static pages, login to your
dashboard through the top right corner
of your journal home page.
Hover over settings in the left
navigation and select website.
From the new frame, click on plugins in
the tabs.
Static pages is in your install plugins
library and you can find it either by
using the search bar, or by scrolling
down to the generic plugins section and
finding it in the list.
To activate static pages, tick the box.
A new expansion arrow will appear beside
the plug-in name. Click on it to expose
the add and edit content button.
Click on edit/add content
Activating static pages has created a
new tab along the top of the website
settings section of your dashboard and
you will be able to access your static
pages through this tab going forward. To
create a new page, click on add static
page at the top of the table. The path is
the text that will be used to create the
permanent URL of this page and we
recommend using, when naming, best
practices of a brief alphanumeric series
of characters in lowercase with no
spaces and no special characters.
The title of the page is what will
appear in your web browser tab or window
head and depending on the layout will
also appear at the top of the page.
The content box is a rich text editor
into which you can enter your page
content. Use the preview button at the
bottom of the page to view how your
content will look once published to your
web page.
When you're satisfied, click Save
you'll see your new page has been added
to the table of live static pages.
Clicking on the path hyperlink will
redirect you to the page on your website.
Clicking on the expansion arrow beside
the title exposes the edit and delete
buttons. Pages can be added, edited and
deleted at any time through this page.
Thanks for watching and we'll see you
again in the next module.