Hello, welcome back to module nine of
setting up your journal with OJS 3.0
workflow settings. Workflow settings
allows you to configure all aspects of
the editorial workflow including file
management, submission guidelines and
requirements, peer review guidelines and
deadlines and email templates and
notifications. This is one of our larger
modules and we've broken it into
multiple units. This video is unit 1
components. Submissions to your journal
may be comprised of multiple parts or
components such as the article text and
related datasets. The components section of the workflow settings is where you'll
be able to manage what subscription
component types are supported by your
journal and can be included with
submissions. To reach components, we begin
on our journal website and access our
dashboard through the top right corner.
Hover over settings in the left
navigation bar and select workflow.
Components is the first tab in the new
frame and the page you land on. OJS has a
default list of possible components
pre-loaded into your dashboard and these
defaults can be restored at any time
using the restore default button. If
there are items in the list that are not
relevant to your journal, click on the
expansion arrow beside the item and
either edit or delete it.
If you're in need of a component type
that is not included in the default list,
you can add it by clicking on add a
component.
Acquired fields for adding a new
component type are the component name
and designation. Enter an appropriate
name.
Designation is a feature still in
development so for now just enter a
double hash.
More information will be released on
this feature in the future. Following
these fields are some additional options
you can activate for this component. If
appropriate, you can indicate that files
of this type are to be sorted by chapter.
Indicate that these files are independent from other published content
or indicate that these components will
always be supplementary files.
Finally, you can use the drop-down menu
to indicate the file type grouping of
this component.
When you're satisfied, click Save.
Once you've edited your components list
to only include components relevant to
your journal submissions, you can use the
order button to reorder the list. The
order is reflected on the submissions
page so it is best practice to place the
most frequently used components near the top of the list for ease of access.
When you're satisfied with your order,
click done.
That concludes our overview of the
components section of the workflow
settings. Thanks for watching and we'll
see you again in the next unit.