Hello, welcome back to module eight of
setting up a journal with OJS 3.0. This
is unit five of website settings
plugins. OJS 3.0 supports a huge number
of plugins to help customize your
journals features. In this unit, I'll
demonstrate how to activate desired
plugins and tell you a little bit about
some of the most commonly used plugins.
To access your website plugin gallery, go
to your dashboard through the link in
the top right corner of your home page.
From the left-hand navigation, hover over
settings and select website.
Plugins is the fifth tab of the website settings section.
The plugins tab is split into install
plugin and the plugin gallery. Install
plugins are all plugins that are
embedded in the default OJS installation
and will also contain any further
plugins you decide to add. Let's begin by
exploring this page.
The install plugins are sorted into
categories to help make it easier to
find what you're looking for. The table
displays the name of the plugin, a brief
description and a checkbox indicating
whether or not the plugin is currently
enabled. Some plugins are essential to
the running of OJS and you'll see that
those ones are enabled and greyed out so
you're unable to accidentally disable
them. Other plugins, you'll be able to
enable or disable as suits you.
The block plugins section, for example,
mirrors what we set as our website
sidebar back in unit 1 of this module
website appearances. This is the back end
way of enabling or disabling those same
content blocks.
Further down the page we'll find other
common plugins that have been enabled
for your site, but that you could disable if you chose to.
Some useful plugins you may want to
consider enabling include the orchid
profile plugin and the google analytics
plugin, both of which are located in the
generic plugins section of the page. We
highly recommend taking your time going
through this page and taking advantage
of the plug-in options to customize and
enhance your journal.
Should you discover there's a feature
you need that isn't already installed in
your OJS instance, head over to the
second tab on this page the plugin
gallery.
In this gallery, you can find additional
plugins that could be installed on your
journal. Again, I encourage you to explore.
If there are any plugins that look
promising, click through on the hyperlink
names and follow the instructions. That
concludes our overview of the website
plugins. Thanks for watching and we'll
see you again in the next module.