Hello, welcome back to module 7 of
setting up a journal with OJS 3.0. This
is unit 3 of journal settings your
sections. Many journals publish different
types of content such as articles
reviews editorials and more. This unit
will help you create the working frames
for different sections you might publish
including naming, defining policies for
the section, setting word limits and
sliding section editors. In this module,
I'll walk you through the process of
creating a new section. To access
sections, we begin back on our website
and then access our user dashboard
through the top right corner. Hover over
settings in the left-hand navigation
menu and select journal.
Sections is the third tab in the journal
settings.
On this page, you'll see the list of
sections already created.
Clicking on the expansion arrow beside a
section name exposes the edit and delete
button. You can edit the parameters of a
section at any time or remove them
completely if they are no longer needed.
For our purposes today, I'm going to
delete the article section and together
we'll recreate it. To delete, hit delete
and then confirm if you hit delete by
accident, you can hit cancel. Let's create
a section by clicking on the link in the
right corner of the box. This brings up a
pop-up form. The required information is
the section name and abbreviation.
The title for the section we are
creating is articles. The abbreviation
we'll give it is ART. Section policy is
a statement that describes the scope of
the section and the type of submissions
that are appropriate. It should include
information about whether the
submissions to the section are
peer-reviewed, indexed and whether there
are any restrictions on who can submit
work to it. It can also include
guidelines for length and formatting
style. Word count allows you to set a
limitation on the abstract word length.
Entering a zero indicates that there is
no limit. If your journal uses review
forms they can be selected from the drop
down menu and apply it to the section.
Our journal currently does not have
review forms. Review forms are created
and discussed in module 9. The indexing
section allows you to opt out of some of
the OJS automatic functions. These will
apply to all items published within the
section. If your journal is not using
peer review on this section, which would
be the case for sections such as
editorials or book reviews, be sure to
check this box. The identify items box
allows you to apply descriptive keywords
to your section which helps with search
engine indexing.
Finally, in this last section you can assign section editors. Section
editors will oversee this specific
section and seperate submissions from
the section to publication. To assign an
editor, click on add item. The drop down
menu will populate with all user
accounts that have section editor roles
enabled for their accounts. Select the
appropriate person. If you'd like to add
a second editor, click on the add item
once more and repeat the process. When
you're satisfied with your work, click
Save.
Lastly, the order of your sections on
this page will be reflected in the table
of contents of your published journal. To
change the order, click on the order link.
You can now drag and rearrange the
sections as you please. When you're
finished, click done. And that concludes
module 7. We'll see you back to the next
module. Thanks for watching.