Hello!
Welcome to the PKP Course: Setting up a Journal
with OJS 3.0, Module 1: Introduction.
My name is Janna, and I'll be your guide through
this new version of Open Journal Systems.
Before we get started, here are a few basics
that you should know.
Firstly, the course is free.
There are no fees to take any of the PKP School
courses.
There is a paid certification option, but
that is optional.
Secondly, the course is completely online.
Everything you need will be available in the
online modules.
Thirdly, the course is entirely self-paced.
You can move through the modules at your own
speed.
And finally, the course is interactive.
Although registration is optional, doing so
will allow you to interact with me and other
students in the online discussions.
Each module will typically consist of a learning
objective, a video, some readings, an activity,
some discussion, and sometimes a quiz to allow
you to check what you've learned.
We hope you will find the course useful, and
we welcome on any feedback you have on how
to make it better.
Once you're ready, let's get started.