Hello, welcome back to module nine of
setting up your journal with OJS 3.0.
This is unit 2 of workflow settings
submissions. The submissions section is
where we'll configure and input
submission guidelines for authors,
submission checklists, metadata
requirements and other related materials.
To access submissions head to your
dashboard using the link in the top
right corner of your home page.
Hover over settings in the left
navigation and click on workflow in the
extended menu.
Submission is the second tab along the
top of the new frame.
The first prompt is for author
guidelines. This is a section over which
you have complete content control thanks
to the rich text editing box.
Bibliographic standards formatting
requirements and timeline expectations
are some of the information elements
that would be appropriate here.
The submissions preparation checklist is
aimed at helping authors ensure that
everything the editorial team needs is
included in their submission. It is
pre-populated with default items, but
those items can be edited or deleted if
they are not relevant. To access those
features, click on the expansion arrow.
This exposes the edit and delete buttons.
You can also add items to the list using
the add item button in the top right
hand corner of the box.
The add item wizard only has one field,
which is a box in which you described
the new checklist item.
When you're satisfied click Save.
Notification of author submission allows
you to direct the system to email the
primary contact of the journal in
addition to emailing the author once the
submission is complete.
Submission metadata allows you to enable metadata fields that can be filled in by
the author at the time of submission as
well as to indicate whether this
metadata element should be a part of the
submission form. The advantage of
allowing your authors to complete the
metadata is accuracy and detail. The
disadvantage is potential
inconsistencies in terms throughout the
journal as you'll be using individual
free text rather than applying a
controlled vocabulary. Be sure to
consider your journals needs and goals
while making metadata element decisions.
Finally, we come to the privacy statement
it is pre-populated with a default text
but can be edited to fully and
accurately reflect your journals
policies. When completed, click Save.
Let's take a quick look at how the
changes we've made will look to authors
making submissions. At the top of your
window, click on view site.
On your homepage, hover over the about
link and select submissions.
First, we can see the submissions
preparation checklist which matches
exactly with what we saw in the
dashboard. Following is the author
guidelines.
You'll note that while I'm logged in
with my journal manager account, an edit
button is visible beside the different
information blocks on the page. Clicking
on this will bring us back to the
submissions page in the workflow
settings of the dashboard. We can also
access our author submissions page in
the dashboard which we discussed in
module 5 by clicking on either the
making new submission or view your
pending submissions links. Not visible on
this page is the submission metadata
section which impacts the actual
submission process within the dashboard.
This is discussed in more detail in the
editing a journal with OJS 3.0 course.
And that concludes our overview of
workflow settings for submissions. Thanks
for watching and we'll see you again in
the next module.