Hello welcome to module 15 of setting up
a journal with OJS 3.0 custom blocks
with plugins. We covered content blocks
initially in module 8 unit one website
appearance and talked specifically about
the information content block in module
eight unit two. The content blocks are
content elements that appear in the side
navigation menu on your journal web site.
OJS 3.0 comes equipped with seven
different sidebar content blocks, but you
can create custom blocks if you need
them by using the custom block plug-in.
To activate this plugin login to the
dashboard using the link in the top
right corner of your journal home page.
Hover over settings in the left hand
navigation and select website.
In the new frame, click on plugins from
the tabs along the top of the frame.
The custom block manager plugin is an
installed plugin and it can be found on
this main page either by using the
search bar, or by scrolling down to the
generic plugins until you see it.
To activate this plugin tick the box.
An expansion arrow will now be visible
beside the name of the plugin. Click on
it to expose the manage custom blocks
link.
To add a block, click on add block.
Give the block a name and input the
content.
When you're satisfied click Save.
The new block will now appear in the
custom blocks table. Click on the
expansion arrow to expose the edit and
delete buttons.
Close the wizard by clicking on the X in
the top right corner.
Let's look at website appearance
settings and see our new block.
You can see our new block has been added to the top of the sidebar and that
it's been annotated to indicate that it
is a custom block. To change its
placement in the sidebar, drag and drop
the block to your preferred location.
Scroll to the bottom of the page and
click Save.
Now let's take a look at how the block
on our sidebar. Click on view site at the
top of the dashboard.
Our custom block is there
in our sidebar, ready to be used by our
readers. And that concludes our overview
of the custom blocks plugin. Thanks for
watching and we'll see you again in the
next module.