Welcome back to module eight of setting
up a journal with OJS 3.0. This is unit
three of website settings
archiving your website content. This unit
is very quick so let's just dive right
in. On your website access your dashboard
from the top right hand corner of the
page.
Hover over settings from the left
navigation and select website.
The third tab along the top of the page
is archiving.
OJS 3.0 has embedded locks and clocks
compatibility and if you wish to use
either of these networks to help with
long-term preservation of your journal,
you can enable it here. Both systems
require you to follow steps outside of
the OJS dashboard. Hyperlinks leading you to those outside communities and
instructions are provided here. All you
have to do within the OJS dashboard is
tick the enabling boxes and click Save.
Remember this step alone does not enroll
your journal in either the locks or
clocks networks, it just enables the
networking within your journal. Be sure
to follow through on joining the
preservation networks by clicking
through to their community websites and
following their instructions and
guidelines. Thanks for watching, we'll see
you back in the next unit.