Hello, welcome back to module eight of
setting up a journal with OJS 3.0. This
is unit two of website settings
information. We're still in the website
settings module on the dashboard and in
this unit we'll be looking at how you
can edit the targeted user content
contained in the information block. We
begin back on our journal homepage. If
you'll recall unit 1 of this module, one
of the settings we've manipulated was
the content of the sidebar. The content
block currently at the top of our
sidebar is called the information block
and it contains pages of targeted
information for readers, authors and
librarians. In this unit we're going to
go over how to customize the information
on these pages. In the top right corner,
access your dashboard.
Hover over settings in the left
navigation and select website.
From the tabs along the top of the page,
select the second tab information.
Editing the information section is very
straightforward. The section audience,
heads, the rich text editing boxes and
the boxes are pre-populated with a
default message aimed at the common
needs of that audience. If the default
text serves your purposes,
there's no need to make any changes. But
you are welcome to customize this text
or even replace it entirely if that's
what best serves your journal. The for
readers section discusses how readers
can create registered accounts and some
of the benefits of doing so. You'll want
to edit this text if your journal
requires reader accounts or
subscriptions to access your content. If
you're going to hyperlink from this page
to content elsewhere,
make sure you test the links.
The four authors section contains broad
information about submitting to the
journal. The default is fairly short
redirecting authors to the author
guidelines and relevant content we've
already input on two different pages of
the website. You can include more
detailed information here if you'd
prefer to. Just make sure to remember to
update any duplicated information on
this page if you make changes to this
content elsewhere on your website in the
future. The four librarian section
contains information about how
librarians can include your journal in
their catalogs and holdings. This is also
a great place to include information and
contacts for institutional subscriptions
if your journal requires subscriptions.
When you're happy with your content,
click save. Your changes we'll go live on
your website immediately. These pages can be edited or updated at any time.
Thanks for watching and we'll see you again in the next unit.