Hello, welcome to module 8 of setting up
a journal with OJS 3.0 website settings.
As the section is quite large and can
get complex, we've broken it down into
six units that correspond to the six
tabs we'll see in the website settings
section of the dashboard.
This video covers unit 1 website
appearance. I will walk you through all
of the ways you can begin to customize
the look of your journal website and
provide you with a brief introduction to
some of OJS 3.0 available templates,
including the new bootstrap 3 base
themes. Let's get started. We begin on the
journal home page and access our user
dashboard from the top right corner.
Hover over settings and select website.
The first tab is appearance and this is
where we'll modify and adjust all visual
aspects of our journal. First, let's
upload a logo by clicking upload in the
pop-up window. Either drag and drop your
local image or click upload a file and
select your logo.
You are also prompted to add alternative
text to your image. Alternative text is
particularly important for communicating
the content of the image in the event
that the image doesn't load. It also
helps describe images to anyone
navigating your site with the help of a
text reader software. When you're
finished, click OK.
We can now see the image we've uploaded and it's related metadata. This logo will
now appear in the header of your website.
I'll point it out later in the video
after we save and view our changes on
the site.
The next section is a rich text editor
box that allows you to crop the footer
of your website. Let's add a bit of
simple text so that we can get a visual
sense of what this content looks like
when viewed on the website.
Now we'll select the theme. OJS 3.0
has three prepackaged themes. For now,
let's stick to the default theme. You can
now select the font style that will be
used in the website. For simplicity, I'm
going to use in Noto Sans, but I
encourage you to explore and select your
favorite.
You can also choose the header banner
color.
If you know the hex value of your
preferred color, you can input it into
the box.
You can also drag the gradient bar
and select a color. Different web
browsers and screens have different
capabilities when it comes to color
display and we recommend going through
the hex code of colors that have been
identified as optimal for websites in
order to ensure a consistent visual
experience for all of your visitors.
If you have an experienced web developer
working on your team, you are welcome to
leverage their expertise and upload
custom CSS files using this wizard.
Sidebar management allows you to change or reorganize the content that appears on
the journals side navigation bar. The
sidebar list indicates what is currently
in the sidebar and the order in which it
appears in the sidebar. The unselected
list has content that is not currently
in the sidebar, but could be added. To
change the sidebar content, just drag and
drop the content boxes into the column
and order you prefer. Moving all of the
items into the unselected will remove
the sidebar altogether.
Homepage image allows you to add an
image to be featured prominently on your
home page. It will be the first thing
that appears in the body of the home
page. Click upload and either drag and
drop or select the file.
If your journal has a favicon it can
be uploaded here and will appear in web
browser navigation bars and in tabs
beside your journal name. If there is any
permanent content you would like to have
appear on your journal homepage such as
a welcome message or a brief
introduction to the journal, you can
input it into the additional content
rich text editor.
Under lists, you can set and adjust
limits to the amount of information
items a page will hold before creating a
second page of content. Finally, if you
have a small version of your logo, you
can upload it as a thumbnail. This
thumbnail will be used by lists such as
the PKP index alongside your journals
description which is something that we
created back in module 7. When you're
satisfied with your changes, click Save.
Now let's view our journal and see how
the changes have manifested in our
websites appearance. Firstly, you can see
the changed banner color and the added
local image to our websites header. Our
sidebar also has some significant
changes. In our home pages body, the first item that we see is the home page image.
Near the bottom of page, we can see the
content that we set in the additional
content section. Finally, we see the
footer that we saved. Now let's head back
to the dashboard and take a look at some
of the other theme options.
From the themed drop-down menu, select
bootstrap base 3 theme. A new menu of
themes should appear under the drop down menu. But if for some reason it doesn't,
click Save at the bottom of the page and
then refresh. We won't go over all of the
different bootstrap theme options, but
there's a lot of variety between them
and I encourage you to explore and test
them out. Let's take a look at the
default bootstrap theme. We'll keep all
the other elements we set previously so
that we can compare how they get
rearranged in the new theme.
Click Save at the bottom of the page
and then on view site. All the elements
we set and the appearance are still
there, but this layout gives your page a
totally different look and feel.
And that concludes our walkthrough of
website appearance. We highly encourage
you to explore this section and
experiment with the different elements.
There are many ways to personalize your
journals and to help it look its best.
Thanks for watching and we'll see you
again in the next unit.