Hello, welcome back to module 7 of
setting up your journal with OJS 3.0.
We're continuing with unit 2 of journal
settings contact. This unit is where we
will set up the contact information for
your journal. It's very straightforward
and will be very quick. Let's dive in. To
edit the journals contact information,
begin on the home page. Access your
dashboard, hover over settings and select
journal. Contact is the second tab along
the top of the new page. In the contact
tab, we're going to input our journal
contact information. The OJS system
requires a mailing address for the
journal, the name and email address of
the journals principal contact and the
name and email address of the journals
technical support contact. The mailing
address has minimal formatting control
so you can write it out as one line or
give it line breaks to help make the
information clearer.
The principal contact is the person at
your journal who is responsible for
corresponding with your readers and
potential authors. This is typically an
editor-in-chief, the assistant editor or
another person with a title in your team.
Their name and email address are
required information, but you can also
add their title, phone number and
affiliation if you choose. The technical
support person is the person on your
team that can help registered users
accomplish tasks within the OJS
interface. Their role is about the system
and infrastructure rather than the
intellectual content of the journal.
Enter their name and email address.
Optionally, you can also add their phone
number. Be sure to click Save when you're
done. This page populates the content in
the about contact section of your
website. And that's it for this unit.
Thanks for watching, we'll see in the
next one.