Hello, welcome back to module eight of
setting up a journal with OJS 3.0. This
is unit four of website settings
languages. OJS 3.0 supports many
different publication languages and in
this unit I'll demonstrate how to
activate them. To access language
settings and to your dashboard to the
top right hand corner of your journals
homepage.
In the left-hand navigation, hover over
settings and select website.
Languages is the fourth tab along the
top of the page.
The default language included in the
initial OJS installation is English.
Additional language packages must be
downloaded from the OJS website and
installed into your existing OJS system
by your site administrator. That work is
beyond the scope of this tutorial, but
I'll quickly show you what you can do as
a journal manager once the language is
installed. All languages that have been
installed will appear on this page the
primary locale radio button allows you
to set the default language of your
website. This is the language the page
appears in. UI stands for user interface
and selecting this option allows your
visitors to choose this language over
the default language when viewing your
webpage. If, for example, we had set
Portuguese as the primary locale, but
left English enabled as a UI language,
visitors to your website would be able
to toggle between the two languages.
Submissions refers to the language of
the submission page. Having more than one language enabled will allow authors to
choose which language the submission
page displays in. Forms refers to all the
different forms that are being used by
different roles in the editorial process
to accomplish tasks. Enabling the
language for forms will provide that
language option when using those forms.
Anytime new languages get added to your
installation or if the language
preferences of your journal change, you
can come back to this page at any time
and adjust your settings and preferences.
Thanks for watching and we'll see you
again in the next unit.