Hello, welcome back to module 10 of
setting up your journal with OJS 3.0.
This is unit 2 of distribution settings
access. This is where you'll manage
access to the journal content. Access
your dashboard through the login link in
the top right corner of your home page.
Hover over settings in the left
navigation and select distribution.
Access is the second tab in the new
frame.
This page is very simple, you just need
to use the radio buttons to indicate
whether the journal will be used to
openly publish the journals content
online or not. More nuanced restrictions
and limitations for access such as
delayed open access or subscription
access only are set elsewhere within the
different stages of the journal creation.
This configuration is for back-end
auditing and configuration purposes.
When your selection is made, click Save.
If your journals publication policies
change over time, you can always come
back to this page and change your
settings. Thanks for watching and we'll
see you again in the next module.