Welcome back to module nine of setting
up a journal with OJS 3.0 workflow
settings.
This is unit four of this module
publisher library. The publisher library
provides a file repository for storing
and quickly sharing common files such as
writing guidelines, author contracts,
release forms, marketing materials. Items
that are stored in the publisher library
can be quickly retrieved and added into
a submission library to be shared with
authors and assistants. To access the
publisher library, we begin on the
journal homepage and then move into the
dashboards through the login link in the top
right corner of the page.
Hover over settings in your left
navigation and select workflow.
Publisher library is the fourth tab in
the new frame.
At present, our publisher library is
empty but you can see that the page has
some default categories that help
organize and sort documents as they are
added. To add a document, click on add
file in the top right corner of the box.
All three items in the wizard are
required items. Begin by naming your file
simple but descriptive titles are
recommended.
Next, choose the type which corresponds
to the sorting categories we saw on the
landing page.
Finally attach a file by either
dragging and dropping or clicking upload
file to open the wizard.
When finished, click okay.
You can now see the item has been added
to the library. Clicking on the
hyperlinked title will download the file.
Clicking on the expansion arrow exposes
the edit and delete button.
This page and its content can be edited
at any time. And that concludes our
overview of the publisher library. Thanks
for watching we'll see you again in the
next module.