Hello and welcome to module four of
setting up a journal with OJS 3.0
registering and logging in. Registered
user accounts play a big role in OJS,
from higher level management right down
to casual readers and creating one is
your first step in taking on your role
in the journals publication cycle. Anyone
can create a user account and in this
video I'll walk you through creating yours.
We begin on the journal homepage, which
we explored in module 3. In the top right
hand corner, you can see two links to
register and to log in. If you already
had an account, you'd click on the log in
link, but we're going to create a new
account by clicking register. This brings
you to a fillable form. Simply follow the
field names to fill in the form. The red
asterisks indicate the mandatory fields
At the end of the forum, new users can
indicate whether they are interested in
acting as a reviewer for the journal.
Selecting this option generates a new
field to where you can indicate your
areas of expertise.
Click enter after you complete each
keyword phrase to generate a new term box.
When you finish completing your
reviewing interest, click register.
Congratulations! You've created a new
account. The new page will indicate that
your registration is complete and you
can see that the top right-hand corner
content has changed to reflect your
username indicating that you are
currently logged in. This page also
begins listing actions you can now take
with your registered account. These
actions will be explored in later
modules. Thanks for watching and we'll
see you again in the next module.