Hello, welcome back to setting up a
journal with OTS 3.0. This is module 3
the reader interface. In this video I
will take you on a brief tour of what
your OJS publication will look like from
your readers perspective. We'll start on
the landing page and then move through
all the different sections so that you
can see what kind of information is
stored where, what your readers will be
able to access and how that access that
information. Let's dive in. The URL of
your journal leads to the splash page. As
you can see, there is a top-level
horizontal navigation bar that contains
the most important content access points
and a sidebar of more specialized
information. The main body of the page
populates dynamically with journal
issues as they are published. You can
also create permanent content such as
this welcome message.
The current tab will bring you to the
most recently published volume of your
journal. As you can see, this page
displays the volume and issue
information of the publication. The cover
image, if one exists, and access to the
content of the issue. The content of this
example issue is split into two sections,
articles and reviews. From this table of
contents, we can also see titles, authors
and different formats in which the
content can be accessed. Clicking on the
title of an article brings you to the
detail page where you'll see the
articles abstract and citation
information. By clicking on the format of
your choice you can also read the
article. Here's an example of the PDF reader.
This article is also available in XML
and in HTML.
The archives tab provides access to all
previously published volumes of the
journal and a brief description of each
one. Clicking through on the issue will
bring you to that table of contents,
which outlines the contents of the issue
and provides access to that content. The
about tab, when clicked on, brings the
reader to a broad about the journal page.
The content of this page is entirely
publisher created and it can contain as
much or as little information as you'd like.
Hovering over the about tab opens a
drop-down menu listing other items that
may be of interest, including the
editorial team, submissions and contact.
The editorial team tab contains as much
or as little information as you decide
and is a space in which you can
introduce the members of your editorial
team. The submissions page gives general guidelines about making submissions to
the journal and is a portal that can be
used to make submissions. Contact
information contains the address of the
journal, information for the principal
contact of the editorial staff and
contact information for the journal web
instant support person. Finally, there is
a search bar which can be used to run
keyword searches for content on your
website. Clicking on your journal title
will bring you back to the splash page.
The content in the side navigation menu
is something that you will determine for
your journal and we'll look at that more
in module 8. This example contains the
information block which is a series of
short information pages tailored to the
interests of specific user groups as
well as information about PKP hosting
and a link to more information about OJS.
Nearly everything we've seen on the
website today is customizable and I'll
walk you through that process in the
subsequent modules. This concludes our
introductory tour of what readers
encounter when navigating around at OJS
publication website. Thanks for watching,
we'll see you again in the next module.