Hello, welcome back to module 12 of
setting up a journal with OJS 3.0 tools.
This is unit 2 statistics. The OJS 3.0
system can be used to generate reports
that track site usage and submissions
over a given period of time. To access
statistics, log in to your dashboard
through the top right corner of your
journal home page.
Hover over tools in the left navigation
and select statistics.
OJS 3.0 has four basic reports that
you can export by clicking on the links.
To generate a custom report, click on the
generate custom report button and follow
the prompts to tailor the report. The
reports are generated in CSV format and
will require a spreadsheet application
such as Excel, Google Docs or LibreOffice
to view and visualize. And that concludes
our overview of the OJS 3.0 tools. Thanks
for watching and we'll see you again in
the next unit.