Hello, welcome to module 6 of setting up
a journal with OJS 3.0 user profile. In
this module, I'll be walking you through
how to configure your personal user
profile within the OJS dashboard.
We begin on the journal homepage in the
top right hand corner. You can log in to
your account. If you are already logged
in, hover over your username and select
the view profile link. We land on the
identity tab. The mandatory fields of
this page are filled in using the
information that you input during the
creation of your user account. There are
options for more information though if,
for example, you have a middle name and
would like to include it, you can input
it here.
You can also include a salutation,
your initials, a suffix
if one applies and your gender identity.
Click Save when you have completed the
form.
Along the top navigation, select the
contact tab.
Under the contact section, you can enter
your contact information. The only
required information is your email
address and your country, both of which
are information that we input during the
creation process. But you also have the
option to input your phone number,
an affiliation if you have one
and your mailing address if you so
choose.
Again, click Save when you're satisfied
with the form.
We'll next move on to the roles tab.
Under rules, you can see the rules that
have been assigned to your account. This
account is enabled as an author and a
reviewer but we can also enable it as a
reader.
If you have enabled that you are a
reviewer, make sure that you're reviewing
interests are entered into the field
down below.
When you are finished, click Save.
Well next move on to the public tab.
Under the public tab, you can build your
public profile. This profile will be
visible to the public on the journal
website. If you have an identifying photo
that you would like to have associated
with your account, you can drag and drop
the file into the section to begin
uploading. You can also click on upload
file to open a browser window. The bio
statement is a rich text editor and you
can populate it with whatever
biographical information you would like
to share with readers. Your profile will
be accessed by readers viewing your
articles, so biographical information
that helps support your expertise is
recommended.
If you have a personal website, enter the
URL
and if you have an orchid ID you can
enter it here. When you've completed all
the changes, click Save.
The password tab allows you to reset
your password if necessary, just enter
your current password, your new password, confirm it and click Save.
Under the notifications tab you can decide what types of submission event notifications
you will receive. With in the OJS system,
the default setting is that you will
receive notifications both in the
dashboard and via email. Personally I do
not like receiving email notifications,
so we are going to select do not send me
an email for these types of
notifications on each of the types. When
you've completed your settings, click
Save.
You have now completely configured your
personal profile within the OJS system.
You can always come back at any time and make further adjustments if necessary.
Thanks for watching, we'll see you next
time.