Hello, welcome module 12 of setting up
your journal with OJS 3.0 tools. This
module has two units and this video is
unit 1 import/export. The import/export
tools allow you to move content between
OJS installations you can import and
export users, publications and article
metadata. To access import/export, login
to your journal through the top right
corner of your journal homepage.
Hover over tools in the left navigation
and select import/export.
The frame you land on is a list of
different plugins installed in OJS
3.0 that facilitate data migration.
Each item is composed of a hyperlinked
title and brief description of what each
tool accomplishes. To use a tool click on
the hyperlink.
Each plugin looks a bit different. Some
will require some configuration such as
the data sight export registration
plugin. But clear instructions and
additional information is included in
the page to help you use the tool. Others
such as the public identifiers XML
plugin are already configured and can be
immediately used to export data from
your journal as well as to facilitate
the import of relevant data files. With
each tool simply follow the instructions
and prompts on the relevant page. Thanks for watching and we'll see you again in the next unit.