Hello, welcome to module 11 of setting up a journal with OJs 3.0 users and roles.
As a journal manager, you're able to
manage user accounts that have been
created for your journal including
creating new accounts, merging accounts,
adjusting roles, adjusting permissions
and removing accounts. This module has
been divided into three units. This video
is unit 1 users. To access users and
roles, login to your dashboard at the top
right corner of your home page.
In the left navigation, hover over users
unrolls
and select users.
This page is a table of all of the user
accounts that have been created for your
journal. It lists the basic information
of first and last names, user names and
email addresses. If you're looking for a
specific user, you can use the search
feature. This allows you to look up a
user using any of these details. You can
also limit the search based on the roles
associated with the accounts.
Roles will be discussed in more detail
in unit 2 of this module. Beside the
search bar is an add user button.
Clicking on this opens a wizard to
create a new user account. The mandatory
fields are the same mandatory fields we
set when creating our personal user
accounts back in module 4 registering
and logging in.
I'll see administrator creating an
account on behalf of the user.
You have the option to generate a random
password for this user as well as to
indicate that the user must change their
password upon their next login. You can
also elect to send the new user a
welcome email. Under more user details
you'll find optional user profile
details.
When you finish the form, click okay.
Whe wizard will then update and prompt
you to attach rules to this new account.
Different roles come with different
permissions and assigning or removing
them will change what dashboard elements
the user has access to and what tasks
within the editorial and publishing
process can be assigned to this user. To
add a role, click add role and select the
appropriate role from the drop down menu.
When you've added all of the necessary
roles, click OK.
Back on the users table, clicking on the
expansion arrow beside the username
exposes several tools that can be used
to manage the user account.
Firstly, you can click on the email
button to open an email wizard if you
need to contact this user.
Simply enter the subject and body and
then click send. You'll note that the two
fields populates automatically with the
email address stored in the user account.
Secondly you can edit the user account
by clicking on the edit button.
You're able to make changes to the
person's name, contact information and
password.
If you're setting a temporary password
for them, you can indicate that the user
must change their password on their next
login. You can additionally make changes
to their country and if you click on the
more user details expansion button,
you can also change nearly all the
details we adjusted while setting up our
personal user accounts back in module 6
user profile. As the journal manager, you
have the capability to access and change
all registered user profiles.
Following, you'll be able to see, and if
necessary, adjust the roles associated
with this account. To remove a role, click
on the X beside the role designation in
the right corner of the row.
To add a roll, click on add roll at the
top of the box. Using the drop down menu,
select the roll you wish to add from the
available options. Enabling the
appropriate rolls activates the account
to be assigned to certain tasks in other
areas of the journal such as section
editors or reviewers. When you've
completed your edits click OK.
From the same list of expanded
management options, you're able to both
disable or fully remove a user account.
Disabling the user will open a prompt to
requesting the reason. Enter an
appropriate explanation and click OK. On
a disabled user, the expanded menu shows
an enable button instead of a disabled
one. Click on it to re-enable the user,
entering the reason once more and
clicking OK.
To remove a user, click remove and then
confirm the action. When you're logged in
as a journal manager and view an account that is not your own, you have the
ability to log in as that user. This
feature allows you to complete actions
on behalf of that user as well as to
view the site through their roles.
Finally, you're able to merge accounts.
This feature is useful if a user
accidentally creates more than one
account among other reasons. To merge
accounts, click on the merge user button.
You will be asked to confirm that you
wish to merge this account with another.
Click OK.
The wizard will close as the page refreshes.
The account you are merging no longer
has a merge button and if you click on
the expansion arrow beside a second
account,
you'll see that the merge button has
changed into merge into this user. The
account we select first is the account
that will be sublimated, while the account
that we select second will become the
permanent account. To complete the
account merge, click on merge into this
user
and confirm.
And that concludes our overview of the
user section of users and roles. Thanks
for watching and we'll see you again in
the next module.