Hello, welcome back to module eight of
setting up your journal with OJS 3.0.
This is unit six of website settings
announcements. Announcements are
temporary content that will appear on
your journals homepage. They are great
for content such as opening and closings
of submission requests for special
issues, event announcements and other
exciting changes happening in your
journal. To post an announcement, we begin on our website's main page and access
the dashboard through the top right
corner of the page.
hover over settings in the left hand
navigation and select website
announcements is the last tab on the
website settings page.
The first thing you're prompted to do is
to enable announcements. To enable
journal managers to post announcements, tick the box.
If you'd like announcements to display
on your website's homepage, tick the box
and set the number of announcements that will display simultaneously on that page.
Enabling announcements creates a new
page that will contain the archived
announcements and only the most recent
announcements to the the number limits set
here will appear on your home page. If
you have any information about
announcements that you would like to
have displayed on your announcement page
such as perhaps a statement on who to
contact with questions about
announcements, you can enter it into this
text box. Let's enter some test content
so that we can see how it will display
when we view it from the website.
If you'd like to add index and control
to your announcements, you can use the
announcement type feature to create type
classes. This feature helps group
announcements for easy search and review in the future. Let's make some sample
types to see this feature in action.
Click on add an announcement type.
Enter a name for your type and click
Save.
After you've saved, you can use the
expansion arrow beside the type name to
either edit or remove it.
The final section is where you'll write
your announcements click on add
announcement to bring up the creation
wizard.
Select your announcement type from the
drop down menu and then follow the forum prompts.
The short description is the content
that will appear with the title on your
main page and on your archived
announcements page.
Description is the full text of the
announcement which is only seen after a
reader clicks through on the
announcement. The short description will
not appear in the description text after
a reader clicks through. The idea is that
the short description is a summary of
the full description, providing a brief
overview while the full description
provides the same information in greater detail.
If you want your announcement posted for a limited time, click on the expiry date
field and select an end date for the
announcement.
When that end date is reached, the
announcement automatically disappears.
To keep an announcement indefinitely, leave this field blank. Click Save when you've
completed the form.
As you add announcements, the
announcement box populates in reverse
chronological order and indicates the
announcement title type and date posted.
Clicking on the title allows you to view
the announcement.
Clicking on the expansion arrow beside
the title allows you to edit or remove
announcements.
Click Save again at the bottom of this
page.
Let's take a look at how the
announcement displays on our website,
by clicking view site at the top corner of
our browser.
Firstly, notice that announcements has
been added to the top navigation bar of
our website.
As for how announcements display on the
homepage, it depends on which layout
you're using. In this instance, we can see
that the announcements display
underneath our permanent content but
above the most recent current issue of
our journal. As for what part of the
announcement displays you'll, see here it
is the brief description. If we click
through, you can see it is the full
description. Let's take a look at the
announcement page.
The active announcements are displayed
from most recent to least recent and are
listed with their titles and brief
descriptions. If we click through to the
full description, we can see that the
brief description is not included on the
page we redirected to. Which is why it's
important to make sure that all vital
information is repeated in both the
descriptions. And with that we conclude
module 8. Thanks for watching and we'll
see you again in the next module.