Hello, welcome to module 10 of setting up a journal with OJS 3.0 distribution
settings. This is another larger module
and we broken it down into multiple
units. This video is unit 1 indexing.
Distribution settings is where we'll
configure settings related to your
search engine indexing, any payments if
you'll be taking them and permissions
and licensing details for publications.
From your journal homepage access your
dashboard through the top right corner of the page.
Hover over settings in the left
navigation and select distribution.
Indexing is the first tab in the new
frame and the page that you land on.
Indexing refers to search engine
indexing and the elements will configure
in this page will affect how your
journal displays in search engine
results and influence how your journal
is indexed by those search engines. Our
first item on this page is the
description. This description displays
with a hyperlink to your website in
search engine results. Fill in the text
box with an appropriate and brief
descriptive statement introducing your journal.
Custom tags are the metadata that get
embedded in the HTML structure of your
journal. They are not visible on your web
page but are read by search engine
crawlers that index your page. The text
input here should use HTML syntax and we
recommend looking up the structure if
you're unfamiliar with it.
Search engine optimization can be a bit
tricky and so we also recommend
leveraging search engine optimization
best practices.
When you're satisfied with your content,
click Save.
This page can be edited and updated at
any time. Thanks for watching and we'll
see you again in the next module.