Hello, welcome back to module 10 of
setting up your journal with OJS 3.0.
This is unit 3 of distribution settings
payments. If you would like to process
payments such as for subscription fees
or publication fees through your OJS
installation, that can be configured in
the payment section of distribution
settings. To access this section, login to
your dashboard through the top right
corner of your home page.
From the left navigation hover over
settings and select distribution.
Payments is the third tab in the new
frame.
Your first prompt is to select the
currency in which you'll be processing
the payments from a drop-down list.
Next use the payment method drop-down
menu to indicate whether payments will
be processed manually by your team or
will be processed through PayPal.
If you select manual, a textbox generates
for you to explain payment instructions
to your readers and authors.
If you select PayPal, you are asked to
input your IPN URL and identify your
seller account. OJS has a PayPal
plugin that will facilitate PayPal
transactions from your website. Once
you've completed this page, click Save.
This feature can be added to your
journal or updated at any time. Thanks
for watching and we'll see you again in
the next module.