Hello and welcome to module 5 of setting
up a journal with OJS 3.0 user dashboard.
Most of the work we do in this course
takes place in the dashboard and it
contains many important sections and
elements. In this video, I'll introduce
you to those elements and give you a
general orientation to the interface. We
begin on the journal's main page. In the
top right hand corner, click on login and
enter the credentials for the account
you created in module 4. Logging in
redirects you to your account's OJS
dashboard which should look a lot like
this one at first. The dashboard is
composed of a thin static navigation bar
along the top of the page and a static
side navigation bar along the left that
create a frame around a dynamic window
with section tabs and content that
changes based on what part of the
dashboard you're looking at. We'll go
through the dashboard systematically,
beginning with the top navigation
options and then working our way down
through the left. In the top left, you'll
see the name of the journal for which
you've created this account. If you have
multiple journals, you can use the
expansion arrow to switch between them.
We next see the language of the page and
then a link to view the journal site.
This link redirects you to your journal
home page. Finally, there is the username.
Hovering over your name activates a
drop-down menu of options to view your
profile or logout. Click on view profile
this section is where you'll be able to
input and edit all of your private and
public personal information. This section
is covered in depth in module six. Note
the different tabs along the top of the
page that indicate different facets of
this section and the help button which
opens a side panel with information
about the page that you're on. Moving
along to the left sidebar navigation, our
first tab is the tasks tab. Clicking on
this opens a pop-up that lists all tasks
that have been assigned to you. We'll
cover what tasks are and assigning them
extensively in the editing a journal
with OJS 3.0 course, so I won't go into
detail on them here. Just know that if
you have them you'll be able to view
them here. You'll note that my tasks tab
currently has a 0 beside it,
but my pop-up shows an item. The number
indicates unread tasks. If I were to mark
the tasks as unread by selecting it and
clicking the mark new button, my tasks
number changes. I can also mark the tasks
as read or delete it. The submissions tab
is where you'll manage submissions to
the journal. This is another section that
is covered in depth in the editing a
journal course and it does not require
any setup. In brief, the my queue tab contains
all active submissions that are
specifically related to you. These can be
submissions you need to assign to a
member of your team, submissions that
have been assigned to you to complete a
task on and submissions that you may
have made to the journal that are being
processed.
You can create a new submission by
clicking on new submission. The all
active tab is only visible to editors
and administrators and allows me to find
any active submission in the system.
Archives show all articles that are no
longer in the editorial workflow, meaning
they have either been published or
declined.
The issues tab is another editorial
function that will be covered in the
editing a journal course.
This section has two parts. Future issues
is where editors create, manage and
publish in progress issues of their journals.
Back issues allows you to review and
edit issues that have been published.
Hovering over the settings tab expands
it into four sections. Each of these
sections are covered in different
modules of this course and most of the
work we will be doing in this course
happens under this tab.
Journal settings are the topic of module
7 and is where will input contextual
metadata to describe your journal and
its policies.
Website settings are the topic of module
8. This is where will customize the
physical appearance of your website
generate some content and explore some
other features that can be included in
your website such as archiving and plugins.
Workflow settings arecovered in module nine and this is the
section in which will configure the
editorial workflow of your journal
including file management, various
guidelines requirements and deadlines
for different roles as well as email
templates.
Distribution settings are the topic of
module 10 and contain settings related
to search engine indexing, payments
permissions and licensing details for
publication.
Users and roles is where you'll manage
registered accounts made for your
journal and the roles and permissions
associated with those user accounts.
This section is covered in more detail in
modules 11, 12 and 13.
The tools section is where you can
deploy certain plugins to pull different
types of data out of OJS as well as
where you can access embedded reporting
and statistics on your journal. These
topics will be covered in module 14 of
this course. And that concludes our
whirlwind orientation of the OJS 3.0
dashboard. As I'm sure you've noticed,
there are a lot of elements working
together within the system to accomplish
different functions. The modules of this
course reflect this interoperability by
building on each other as they walk you
through the step-by-step process of
developing your journal. Thanks for
watching and we'll see you again in the
next module.