Hello, welcome back to module 10 of
setting up your journal with OJS 3.0.
This is unit 4 of distribution settings
permissions. In this section, we'll
configure settings around copyright and
licensing of materials submitted to and
published by your journal. To access
permissions, login to your dashboard
through the top right corner of your
journal home page.
Hover over settings in the left
navigation and select distribution.
Permissions is the fourth tab in the new
frame.
The first section of the page is a rich
text editor for your copyright notice.
The copyright notice is meant to inform
regarding the underlying claim to
copyright ownership in a published work.
In other words, use this section to
inform those interacting with your
journal about who owns the copyright to
materials published in your journal.
If you require authors agree to the
copyright notice as part of the
submissions process, tick this box.
OJS will automatically generate
copyright notices on each item published
in your journal and the following two
items configure that setting. Firstly,
indicate whether copyright year is based
on the issue publication or the article
publication date.
Secondly, indicate who the copyright
holder of the materials will be.
Licensing differs from copyright because
it defines how material can be used
rather than who has legal ownership of
the materials. Using the drop-down menu,
indicate what type of usage license
should be applied to the materials in
your journal. The drop-down menu is
pre-populated with the different types
of Creative Commons licenses. But if you
are using a different license, select
other and provide a URL to the license
if one is available.
Finally, copyright and licensing
information is permanently attached to
your published content. If for some
reason you need to reset the stored
permissions to update information, you
can use the reset article permissions
button at the bottom of this page to
create a rollback across all
pre-existing content. When you've
completed the settings click Save.
This concludes our overview of the
different elements of the distribution
settings. Thanks for watching and we'll
see you again in the next module.