Hello, welcome to module 16 of setting up
a journal with OJS 3.0 getting help.
We recognize that there's no way for us
to include all possible information into
our pkp school courses and this extra
module aims to help you discover the
different ways in which you can access
more detailed support as you develop
your journal with OJS 3.0. The first
recourse is embedded in your journal's
dashboard.
Most pages in the dashboard have a help
button.
Clicking on it will open a sliding
window with information about the page
that you are on and what you can do
there. If you scroll to the top, you'll
see you have access to a table of
contents.
This exposes all of the different help
pages embedded in the dashboard and you
can use the hyperlinks to look for
information that you need.
Or you can use the previous and next
buttons at the bottom of the page to
read through like a manual. This content
is sourced from the PKP documentation
Github and is updated in tandem with
software upgrades so should always be
current. If you require more in-depth
assistance, head to the PKP main website
pkp.sfu.ca. From the top navigation
you can see there is a link called
support.
Under it are the different places you
can look for further assistance.
The PKP community forum is a place where
you can ask questions and review
questions that have been post.
Here you can leverage the expertise of
the PKP community members. You're also
welcome to assist in answering questions
and to join in any of the forum
conversations. There is a specific area
for frequently asked questions, as well
as a dedicated questions sub-forum.
The documentation link leads you to the
PKP wiki page. The wiki is a web of
collected information sources. You can
use the search bar to look for something
specific, or you can dig around through
the descriptive links for a more organic
search.
PKP school is another source of
additional information.
Here you'll be able to find courses that
are similar to this one and that focus
on providing skills training for the
different roles within and OJS
installation. Finally, the education and
training link leads you to further
resources, particularly you'll find user
guides that can assist you in developing
your knowledge and understanding of
different facets of the public knowledge
project software suites.
And let's not forget that you're always
welcome to leave your questions in the
comments of this course and we'll do our
best to help you find the information
that you need. And that concludes our
course setting up a journal with OJS 3.0.
Thank you for watching and learning with
us and we look forward to reading your
journals.