Welcome back to module nine of setting
up a journal with OJS 3.0 workflow
settings.
This is unit 3 of this module review.
This section controls the parameters of
the submission review process, including
deadlines, forms, peer review parameters
and guidelines and policies regarding
competing interests. The review
guidelines are not visible on the public
website and are used by editors and
reviewers working on submissions within
the dashboard. That process is discussed
in detail in the editing a journal with
OJS 3.0 course. Let's take a look at
setting up these features. To access the
review settings page, go to your
dashboard using the link at the top
right hand corner of your page.
Hover over settings in the left hand
navigation and select workflow.
Review is the third tab along the top of
the new window.
Your first prompt is regarding the
setting of review deadlines. You can
choose to set a time limit defining how
many weeks a reviewer has to either
accept or decline a request to review a
submission and how many weeks they have
to complete their review of that
submission. If you choose to add limited
timeframes be sure to include them in
the review guidelines below so that your
reviewers are aware of these policies
and deadlines.
Following, you have the ability to set
automated email reminders. We'll talk
about the content of these emails in
module nine unit five. Automated
reminders require some configuration by
your site administrator. But once the
task is completed, these grayed out boxes
will be active and you can use the
drop-down menus to select the reminder
email schedule.
Review forms are used by reviewers to
help structure their feedback on
submissions forms are entirely in the
control of journal managers and are
created in a two-step process, beginning
with create review form in the top right
corner of the box.
Give your new form a title and then
complete a brief description and
instructions for use. click Save.
To add items to your form, click on the
expansion arrow beside the title and
click Edit.
In the pop-up wizard, the data we just
entered in the create window will all be
located in the first tab. It can be
edited here as well click on the second
tab form items.
In this section, we'll create items to be
included in the form by clicking on
create new item.
The rich text editor gives you lots of
space and flexibility in crafting each
of your form items.
After you define them, you have the
option to make this items completion a
required action. You can also elect to
inform the submission author through an
automated email if this form is going to
be used to review their submission. Item
type refers to the kind of response the
reviewer will be able to make to this
checklist item such as to enter a short
text blurb or tick a box. Using the
drop-down menu, select the item type that
facilitates the appropriate response to
your checklist item.
If you want your reviewer to select a
response from a list of preset options
such as to select whether the submission
is ready for publication, needs to be
revised or should be rejected, you can
set these options using the response
options. To add a response option click
add item.
When you've completed the form, click
Save.
If you need to edit the items or you
want to remove it, click on the expansion
arrow to expose the edit and delete
buttons.
Repeat this process for every item you
wish to add to the form the third tab in
the wizard is the preview form.
Clicking on it will show you what your
review form will look like to those
using it.
This can help you tweak the item type
and ensure that the form you're creating
matches with your use intentions of the
form. To close the wizard, return to the
review form tab
and click Save at the bottom. When your
form is ready to be used
be sure to check the active button.
If your Journal is using blind review,
enable the function to send relevant
instructions and information. Clicking on
the hyperlink text will open a window
with more information about this feature.
Competing interest is an area where you
can define your journals competing
interest disclosure policy. It is a rich
text editor and you can customize this
section as best serves you. If you
require a competing interest statement
from the reviewer, tick this box.
The review guideline section is a space
in which you can define what is expected
of your reviewers provide them with
review criteria to help them assess the
submission and any guidelines or
policies that would help reviewers
complete their work such as that
deadlines to accept review or the
deadline to submit their review. It is a
rich text editor and you can complete it
as best suits your journal.
Following you can select whether the
review process will be double-blind,
blind or open using the drop-down menu.
Finally, we come to reviewer access which tweaks how and when reviewers can access
submissions they have been asked to review.
If you would like to either enable one,
click review access or stipulate that
reviewers must agree to review before
they are able to access submission files.
Tick the appropriate boxes. When you've
completed the settings to your
satisfaction, click Save. This concludes
our overview of the review workflow
settings. Thanks for watching and we'll
see you again in the next module.