Hello, welcome back to module 11 of
setting up a journal with OJS 3.0 users
and roles.
This is unit 2 of this module roles. User
roles govern who can access what in the
editorial workflow. OJS 3.0 provides a
flexible user role system that allows
you to tailor these roles to your
journals needs. To access rules, login to
your dashboard through the top right
corner of your journal home page.
Hover over users and roles and select
roles.
OJS is pre-loaded with 17 different roles
and they are listed in this table. The
table lists the roles by name and
abbreviation and then indicates the
different stage assignments that can be
activated for the role. This means that
users with, for example, the role of
journal editor are able to assign tasks
from all stages of production to
appropriate users. But the production
editor is only able to assign copy
editing or production tasks to the
appropriate users. They are unable to
assign tasks related to submissions or
reviews. To change these role based
abilities tick or untick the boxes
related to the responsibility you wish
to change. Clicking on the expansion
arrow beside the role name exposes the
edit and remove buttons.
To edit a role, click Edit.
For existing roles, the permission level
will be grayed out and cannot be changed
through editing, but you are able to edit
the role name as well as the
abbreviation for the name.
Following is another opportunity to
adjust the stage assignment powers of
this role.
Finally you can indicate whether you
want this role title to appear in the
contributor list and whether you'd like
to allow users to self register for this
role as they can with readers and
authors. When you've completed your edits,
click OK.
In addition to editing existing roles,
you are also able to create new roles by
clicking on the create new role button
in the top right corner of the box.
When creating a role you are able to
select the ideal permission level. As we
saw while editing the roles, the
permission level becomes locked after
the role is created.
Following we see the same fields we
covered while editing roles. When you've
completed the form, click OK at the
bottom.
For more information about what
permissions are associated with each
role, click on the Help button at the top
right of the page.
Scroll down to the roll section.
A brief list of the different permission
levels can be found here. And that
concludes our overview of roles. Thanks
for watching and we'll see you again in
the next module