Hello, welcome to module 13 of setting up a journal with OJS 3.0 the Google
Analytics plugin. Google Analytics is one
of the optional plugins that you can
activate for your journal and connecting
your Google Analytics account through
your journal website will enable the
gathering of all kinds of use and visit
data on your journal. To activate and
configure the google analytics plugin,
log in to your dashboard to the top
right corner of the journal homepage.
Hover over settings in the left
navigation and select website.
From the tabs along the top of the new
frame, select plugins.
On the install plugins list, either used
the search to find Google Analytics or
scroll down to generic plugins in the
table and manually find Google Analytics.
In order to activate Google Analytics
within OJS, tick the box.
An expansion arrow is now visible beside
the plugin named click on it to expose
the plugin settings and click on
settings.
Before you can start using Google
Analytics on your home page, you must
first create a Google Analytics account.
If you have not already done so you can
click on the Google Analytics site link
to complete this step. Once you've got
your account setup, input your Google
Analytics account number into this box
and click OK to save your setup. Please
note that it can take up to 24 hours for
this update to push through onto the
website and for Google Analytics to
begin reporting data. And that concludes
our overview of the settings and
configuration of Google Analytics for
your journal. Thanks for watching and
we'll see you again in the next module.