Hello, welcome back to module 11 of
setting up a journal with OJS 3.0 users
and roles.
This is unit 3 of this module slight
access options. Under the site access tab, you can turn off public user
registration or limit access to the
reader facing site to registered users.
To access site access options, login to
the dashboard through the top right
corner of your journal home page.
Hover-over users and roles in the left
navigation and select site access options.
Manipulating site access is very easy,
it's simply a matter of ticking or
unticking boxes to enable described
features. The first section of the page
defines two options for additional site
and article access restrictions.
You're able to select whether users must
be registered and logged in to view the
journal site meaning any content on your
website not just the journal issues as
well as select whether users must be
registered to view open access content.
You can select either both or neither
and you can change this at any date if
your journal changes its policies. The
second section is user registration For
this section, you must select only one
option. Option one, the default, is that
users can register a user account with
the journal. Option two is to have the
journal manager register all user
accounts with permissions to editors and
section editors to register a new
reviewer accounts. When you've completed
your modifications, click Save. And that
concludes this unit as well as concludes
module 11. Thanks for watching and we'll
see you again in the next module.