Welcome back to module nine of setting
up your journal with OJS 3.0 workflow
settings.
This is unit five of this module emails.
OJS sends a number of emails during
various stages of the editorial workflow,
as well as other actions such as
registration and submission
acknowledgement. The settings of the
section allow you to edit the signature
attached to the email, as well as change
the default messages sent in each type
of email. To access emails, log in to your
dashboard using the login link in the
top right corner of your journal home
page.
Hover over settings in the left
navigation and select workflow.
Emails is the fifth tab at the top of
the page.
The first item on the page is the
signature attached to automated emails.
It has a default signature, but it is a
rich text editing box that can be
customized whatever you prefer.
Following, use the option to set a
bounce address. Any undelivered emails
will send an error message to this
address. Activating this feature will
requires some assistance from your site
administrator.
Finally we come to the email templates.
OJS 3.0 is preloaded with 62 templates
all arranged in the following table. Some
templates are essential and have their
enabled tick boxes greyed out. Others are
optional and can be disabled as that
serves here. Clicking on the expansion
arrow beside the template name allows
you to edit the email or reset it to its
default settings.
When editing emails, it's important to
note that the text in scroll brackets
are system commands that Auto generate content. When you've completed your edits,
click Save. To add a new template click
on the add email template link at the
top of the box.
The form requires a name subject and
body content. When you've completed the
form, click Save. When you're satisfied
with all of the changes that you've made
to your templates, scroll down to the
bottom of the page and click Save.
Email templates can be edited at any
time and the defaults can all be
restored at once using the reset all
templates button and that concludes our
overview of the email workflow settings.
Thanks for watching we'll see you again
in the next module.