Hello, welcome to module 7 of setting up
your journal with OJS 3.0 journal
settings. This section is quite large so
we've broken it down into multiple units.
This first unit is the masthead. In the
masthead, we'll be inputting a lot of the
contextual metadata for your journal.
Let's dive in. We start back on the
journal homepage. Access your dashboard by hovering over your username and
clicking on the dashboard link from the
left navigation. Hover over the Settings
tab and select journal. The masthead is
the first tab under the journal settings.
The masthead is where we'll input the
consistent publishing metadata for your
journal. The required fields are the
journal name and journal initials. Fill
in your publication's full name. It will
appear in your website's header. The
journal initials serve an internal
function.
You can also add a preferred
abbreviation which will appear in your URL.
The name of your publishing body can be
input
into the publisher section.
If your journal has an ISSN,
that information can be input here. The
system validates ISSN so I'm not able to
input a false one. Journal summary is for
a brief description of your journals
publishing interests and purpose. For our
example, we'll plug in some simple
pre-selected text. The masthead section
of the page is a rich text editor where
you can introduce all of the people on
your journal team including your editors,
directors and other persons. You have
complete control over how this text
looks, what information you choose to
include and what level of detail suits
your purposes. This section populates the
editorial team page on your journals
website and will be viewed by the public.
I've created some sample text to help
give you an idea of what this could look
like. So as we can see, we have the title,
we have the name, we have their
affiliation and we have a specific
formatting that helps highlight that
each subsection is related to the title.
The about the journal section is another
rich text editor in which you can input
as much or as little information as best
suits your journal. The description of
the section makes suggestions as to what types of content you may want to include
in this section. If there are any
sections you'd like to include but you
are uninspired in drafting the content,
reviewing the OJS published journals for
inspiration or examples can be a big
help. The content input into this section
displays on your journal website and
populates the about the journal page. For
example purposes, here's what some of
this content might look like. This
example has a focus and scope for the
journal, information about the open
access policy, a copyright notice, a
privacy statement and some information
about sponsorship. Now that we've filled
in everything, click Save. The changes
will push through to your website
immediately. If you need to change, edit
or add information at any time, just come
right back to the masthead page and
follow the same steps. Thanks for
watching, we'll see you again in the next
module.